# Come on
哎哟
# 你这么大了还要坐这个车啊
Still want to ride the stroller when you are this big?
# 哈喽 大家好
Hey guys
# 今天带着女儿 儿子老婆来摘下葡萄
Today I brought my family here to pick some grapes
# 现在反正也七月份了吧
It’s already July
# 这个葡萄熟了的季节
The grapes are ready in this season
# 来摘点巨峰
Let’s pick some Jufeng (A species of grapes)
# 因为我平时也很喜欢吃巨峰葡萄
Because I like really like that species
# 走了
Let’s go
# 这个啥子品种安
What’s this species?
# 这个是我们的醉金香它的口感哈
It’s called Zuijinxiang. It has a good texture
# 啥子味道的哦
How does it taste like?
# 它是那种
It is
# 纯甜而且有一种有一股很好的香味
Pure sweet with a pleasant aroma
# 可不可以摘一个来试一下
Can I pick one to try?
# 可以 你摘一个来尝
Sure, go for it
# 这个没有籽
This is seedless
# 你看他看到你吃
The baby is watching you eating!
# 这个葡萄好涩口 好酸啊 里面是甜的
Gosh it’s actually pucker and sour. Only the core is sweet
# 这个皮跟李子一样 跟李子有点（像）
Its skin is like plums’
# 要不要吃一个沺沺
Tiantian, you want one?
# 有点涩口
It’s a bit astringent
# 但是里面这个我觉得好像比巨峰还要更甜一点
But the inside is even sweeter than Jufeng
# 皮不吃皮不吃
Don’t eat the skin
# 酸不酸
Is it sour?
# 酸的
Guess it is
# 不酸啊
It’s not that sour
# 这个葡萄比较好
This bunch is good
# 它已经熟透了
Ripe on the tree
# 像你们种那个都是专家喽嘎
You guys are the experts on planting these
# 这个我们还是已经十哒十年了
Yeah we have been farming these for 10 years
# 像这一串就是熟透了样
It’s ripe when it’s like this bunch, right?
# 哦 对对对
Exactly
# 像这一串它已经熟透了 你看它它全部是一种金黄色的哈
This bunch is thoroughly ripe. Look at the golden color
# 给人的感觉
It feels like…
# 你先品尝一个嘛
Have a try first
# 来
Here you go
# 好
Aright
# 这个口味就很好
It should taste really good
# 嗯
Yes
# 这个皮子不怎么涩口
The skin is not that astringent
# 但是这个
But
# 这个有点不一样是啥子安
It has one difference
# 它不像巨峰一挤那个肉就出来了
The fruit doesn’t pop out like Jufeng
# 哎 对
Yeah right
# 这个只有连这皮子一哈吃
You have to eat it with the skin
# 哎 对这个 就是这样的 它的这个品种不一样
Yeah it’s like that. It’s a different species
# 因为很多品种不一样
It’s because of the species
# 好 差不多了 我们去摘点巨峰嘛
Alright. Let's go for some Jufeng
# 哎 要得 去摘点巨峰嘛
Alright. Let’s go for Jufeng
# 巨峰
Jufeng
# 那边的是不哦
Are they on that side?
# 我们这边的品种很多
We have a lot of species here
# 嗯 走嘛
Alright, let’s go
# 抓一下下没事
It’s okay for him to touch it
# 等下他要吃手
He’ll put his fingers in his mouth later
# 这个嘛 这个是沉香
These down here are called Chenxiang
# 它都是一种果香味
It tastes really fruity
# 它的甜度啊
Its sugar percentage
# 是已经达到20%以上了 给人的感觉很舒服
Is above 20 percent. Tastes really comforting.
# 那这个就是沉香
That’s Chenxiang
# 哎 这都是沉香
Yeah, all these
# 有股花香味
It’s got a fragrance of flowers
# 哦 对
Yeah right
# 哪个最适合做葡萄酒
Which species is the best for winemaking?
# 做葡萄酒来说 这个夏黑哈做葡萄酒
Summer Black is the best to make wine
# 跟我们的这个光辉 跟我们的早巨峰
Mix it with Guanghui, Zaojufeng
# 还有我们的这个早霞玫瑰的这三个品种
And also the Zaoxiameigui
# 混合做的葡萄酒哈
The wine made from a hybrid of those
# 那个喝起来真的是舒服
tastes really comforting
# 好多品种到底一哈有
How many species are there in total?
# 总共这个院子里的品种哈是
In total, this farm has about
# 20余种20多种哦
More than 20 species
# 这样啊
Got it
# 不知道是什么
I don’t know what that is
# 好 你推吧
Alright, you push
# 慢点推啊
Take it slow
# 你别推到沟里去了
Don’t push it into the ditch
# 因为它颗粒啊稍微的偏小一点点的
This one has smaller fruits
# 但是它口感非常好
But it tastes extra good
# 而且它的品质 你看我们的肉质 是非常非常的细嫩的
Its texture is really smooth
# 而且很细嫩
Really smooth
# 给人的感觉吃起很舒服
Tastes really comforting
# 我还是觉得这个更好吃
This one is my personal favorite
# 其它的我
All the others…
# 让我选的话我还是吃这个
I’ll go for this if I have a choice
# 就那种黢黑的就是熟了嘎
The really black ones are ripe, right?
# 因为我们呢 就是自然红的
Yeah we let them ripe on the tree
# 自然熟的 全部都自然熟
All of them
# 你看
See
# 虽然说有一点点红啊
Even though this one is still a little bit red
# 而且那是已经熟透了
It’s already totally ripe
# 这个是不是摘回去了要放一段时间哦
Do we need to let them rest for some time when we take them home?
# 不不不 你放哈冰箱更好吃一下
No. But they are better after refrigerated
# 冻一哈更好吃哦
Cool them down and they taste better
# 你看这串葡萄已经成熟了的
See, this bunch is ripe
# 而且这个
And
# 看这个一串有好重哦
This bunch is heavy
# 这个一串是一斤 一斤多一点点的
About 1 jin (500 gram), or a little bit above
# 所以说我们的巨峰跟市面上的巨峰不一样
Our Jufeng is different from the ones on the market
# 这怕没得一斤的哦
It’s not 1 jin I guess
# 这个看起来很舒服的
It looks comfortable
# 嗯
Yeah
# 好差不多了
OK I think these should be enough
# 我那一篮都有5斤了害怕都有 够了
Only the ones in my basket are more than 5 jins. Enough
# 这个蜂蜜味的
This one tastes like honey
# 而且它是一个蜂蜜味带纯甜
It’s pure sweet plus honey
# 而且给人的感觉是很舒服的
Gives you a comfortable feeling
# 来 宝贝尝一下蜂蜜味的
Come on baby, taste the honey flavor ones
# 是什么味道
See how it tastes like
# 过来
Come here
# 好不好吃
See whether it’s good
# 看下你有没有蜂蜜
See whether you can have some honey
# 就是我觉得不是不甜
I think it’s sweet
# 它是一个蜂蜜的味道一下子就把这个葡萄的味道给抢了
But the honey flavor really takes the grape flavor away
# 蜂蜜的味道抢了葡萄的味道我觉得
It takes the place of the grape flavor
# 今天摘了四五斤葡萄这个
Today we picked about 5 jins of grapes
# 葡萄甜还是挺甜的
The grapes are sweet
# 但是这个棚里面热呀
But it’s really hot in this greenhouse
# 真的是热
It’s steaming
# 我女儿热的她都不想走路要爸爸抱
My daughter quitted walking because of the heat and she wants to me to carry her
# 你也热
Haha you feel hot too
# 我们赶紧出去
Let’s get out of here
# 儿子也热
My son feels hot too
# 真的很热
Gosh it’s burning
# 哦 想睡觉了 是不是
Oh maybe you want to have a nap
# 然后我们这个家庭出来嘛
Today I brought my whole family out
# 反正就摘摘水果啊什么还是挺好的
It feels great to pick the fruits and all
# 虽然说这个棚里面的老板都说了
Although the owner said that
# 棚里面的这个价格要比外面摊上面的价格要略贵一些
The grapes here have a higher price than the outside markets
# 这个应该也能理解
It’s understandable
# 因为边摘的时候都在吃
Because we ate some when we were picking
# 所以贵那么一点是正常的
It’s okay to be a little bit more expensive
# 好啦 本期视频到这里啦 拜拜
Alright, that’s it for this episode
# 有空的时候带家人出来
Take your family out when you got some time
# 好好放松放松
and have a good relax